ALEX LEE

Human-Computer Interaction and Design

Contact Info (925) 852-1320 aml023@ucsd.edu

PROFILE

Senior student studying Cognitive Science with a Specialization in Human-Computer Interaction and a minor in Design at the University of California, San Diego. My interest in design is rooted in efficiency and simplicity. I believe that anything and everything can be improved through simple design. My goal is to combine my personal interests and academic background to help a tech-oriented company achieve their goals, increasing my knowledge of design along the way.

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

- A goal-oriented, analytical and intuitive problem-solver
- Quick and adaptable in any given situation
- Studious and eager to absorb as much knowledge as possible
- Punctual, especially when it comes to meeting deadlines

EXPERIENCE

UX/UI Designer

The Cambridge Project - UCSD

2017 - 2017

Created low-fidelity mockups of an app that was intended to guide people with mental disabilities through exercises assigned by their doctors and track their progress on a weekly basis. With a team of five students at UCSD and three students from Cambridge, we created a branding scheme and multiple wireframes through the process of iterative design.

UX/UI Designer

Friendpool - UCSD

2016 - 2016

In a team of three, built a rough prototype of a friendly carpooling web application intended for use by the students of UCSD in order to aid hectic commutes. In the short time-frame of 10 weeks, we did the necessary needfinding, created multiple prototypes (paper and digital) of the app interface, implemented our design in HTML and CSS, and A/B tested via Google Analytics.

EDUCATION

University of California, San Diego

2014 - 2018

Senior studying Cognitive Science with a Specialization in Human-Computer Interaction and a minor in Design.

PROFICIENCIES

- Well versed in Adobe Creative Cloud programs including Photoshop, InDesign, Lightroom, Premiere Pro, Experience Design, and Illustrator.
- Working knowledge of Microsoft Office applications such as Word, Powerpoint, and Excel.
- Experience collaborating with others using Google Drive, Slides, and Docs.
- Basic knowledge of computer programming languages such as HTML, CSS, and Java.
- Avid photographer and videographer.